let's talk about the chain stitch we're
gonna start making our chain by making a
slipknot you'll want to make sure you
leave a 6-inch tail so you can weave
that in when you're done drape the tail
over your index finger and just wrap it
around pinch the loop and then go
through that loop and pull through your
tail and then tighten it by pulling up
on the string attached to the ball and
you've got your loop
then take your crochet hook and just
insert it through the loop and if you
pull in the loose end here you can
gently tighten it around your hook you
don't want to pull too tight you want to
make sure you can slide it back and
forth on your hook now you need to get
the yarn on your left hand so wrap it
around your pinky and bring your index
finger under it and you're ready to
start chaining take the hook and go
under the yarn hold onto the loop that's
on your hook with your pointer finger
grab it here and then twist your hook so
let's point it down and you're gonna
pull it through the loop and pull it off
and then turn your hook back up you'll
want to pull the stitch back on the fat
part of the hook so you don't make your
stitches too tight readjust and pinch
the part of the chain you've started to
make
then scoop your yarn catch it on the
hook
twist the crochet hook so the hook part
is facing down and then you come through
that loop that's on your hook and off
and bring it back on adjust your tension
a bit and you can hold on to this loop
again adjust your tension and fingers
here and we're gonna do it again
so you scoop the yarn there twist your
hook through the loop and back on to the
main part of the hook scoop the yarn
pull it through the loop back on to the
hook and we keep doing it and as you get
the hang of it you can go a bit faster
[Music]
once your chain starts building
underneath the hook you'll want to stop
every so often and adjust your fingers
and pinch closer to the top of the chain
[Music]
and that's all there is
you
[Music]